Morning.
Good morning.
Good morning. How are you today?
Sign us out and ask for more than that.
For more than that.
It's raining here.
We'll get to that soon. Freezing rain.
Oh.
The joys of the North.
Here it's freezing rain if it's below 60.
OK.
All right. Welcome to day three.
Here today we'll be finishing up on our
brownfield work, but before I do that,
I wanted to share a couple of things.
First is I I remembered what the question
was that was asked earlier and it was
about Azure DevOps and using Azure DevOps
with.
With Copilot and I found two things.
There are two extensions in the
marketplace that I think are relevant
here.
One is this the Git DevOps existent which
is basically allows you to use.
A GitHub Copilot with Azure DevOps.
It's it's built by a team at Microsoft,
but not the not the GitHub Copilot team.
And then there is a an extension that
allows you to use the Copilot CLI.
In Azure DevOps pipelines.
So if you were going to be doing things
like what I showed yesterday of having a
pipeline run a prompt to do a evaluate
the you know a commit or the like you
this this tool should allow you to do
that.
So I put this in a in the folder and
committed this to the repo so you could
have access to that and it's actually if
you do a search in the in in the in the
extensions and look for GitHub copilot.
And Azure DevOps,
it was the top two things that popped up.
The other one is a table I've found or
built.
That just compares the business and
enterprise versions based the idea here
or the what I found is that basically
it's $19.
00 a month for a business per per user
per month for business, a business.
For a business license and what what I
thought was interesting is what is that
the the requirements are that you have a
a a GitHub organization established.
So that's how they track how many people
they should be billing is how many people
to join the org.
But do you only need to have one person?
To create the org.
So if you were a single person shop,
you could create an organ in in GitHub
and then be able to get access to Copilot
for $19.
00 a month and that gives you essentially
A cheaper way to get the.
Pro Plus license and and you get access
to some of the the business level
configuration as well as the org level
instruction files. So that's something I.
You might want to that might be
applicable to you. All right.
Any questions on those two or anything
that we want to discuss before we get
into today's material?
OK then, let's see. Let's start off here.
No, that's not what I wanted.
This is the guy I wanted. All right,
so um.
So the first exercise I I wanted to start
off this morning is to is to fork a repo.
This is the AI assisted software
development brownfield repo that we want
to work with.
The idea is we want to be able to explore
a.
Unfamiliar code base,
so this is a code that we haven't seen
before.
What I'd like you to do is to fork the
repo so that and I'll paste the URLs into
chat in just a minute,
but fork the repo and then clone that
forked repo.
You also need to create a GitHub personal
access token and store that in an
environment variable so that it's
available to a Visual Studio code,
and so you'll need to restart Visual
Studio code once you've established that.
That uh, environment variable.
So let me grab those.
Two URLs. One is for the repo.
And the other one is for.
And the other one is for the page in in
GitHub that you can create your personal
access token.
So let's get started on that.
And the scenario that that I'm thinking
of is that Doug here you are that you've
been basically handed this.
This new application that you need to
need to basically try to understand so we
can use some of the things that we
learned yesterday to actually interrogate
the code base and figure out in that how
what what the what are the issues that we
would have with that code base and the
like and we'll do that in the next
exercise.
So but for right now we just want to be
able to get this repo available locally
to our so that we can work with it.
All right, questions.
Chris.
Yeah, a quick one, John.
I've been putting all of these folders in
the same workspace.
Is that gonna cause issues with the
copilot context?
Um.
Well, yeah,
that's 'cause it'll all be part of the
same code base at that point.
You might want to, you know,
bring this into a a separate folder and
and work with it on its own.
Sure. OK. Thanks.
Um, for the personal access token,
am I supposed to be creating a fine grain
token or a classic token?
I would do a classic token.
It's a little bit easier to you don't
OK.
have to do as much.
If you're doing this in a production app,
you would want to use a fine grain token
just for security purposes.
OK. Thanks.
Sure.
Shout out if you have another question.
And why don't you all go ahead and raise
your hand and take your hand down when
you've actually completed the exercise?
Just so you know,
this is a fork of an existing repo in
GitHub that I've created.
I did some looking around and found this
this project.
I looked for something that wasn't too
big because I didn't want it to be
overwhelming, but had a.
A a decent amount of code that we could
use and it has a a decent number of of
things about this code base that we would
probably want to address.
So I took a fork of this and now you're
being now you're essentially taking a
fork of my fork.
And the reason for the the fork is that
this will give you a a standalone copy of
the of the repository that you can push
changes to.
2.
So should we only copy the main branch?
Should we do the whole?
Just do the main branch.
Sorry,
where do we set the GitHub token
environment variable?
Where do you set it?
You you you can you can either go into
your into Windows and set it there or you
can you can use the you know you can use
PowerShell or something else like that to
actually set it programmatically.
And the token we just says repository
access public repositories or is it is it
our own all all all repositories?
You're talking about for the the personal
access token.
Token. Yeah.
Well,
you you basically need it for this one
repo.
But you know you can create it with this
with whatever permissions that you that
you want, as long as you can.
Use it within Visual Studio code to
actually use a GitHub CLI.
OK.
Anyone need some help?
Does the user environment variable or a
system or doesn't doesn't it matter?
It doesn't matter.
I don't think that matters.
And then if you're done with the exercise,
you can go ahead and lower your hand.
That way I'll have a sense of when
everybody's finished.
You need any help, Rebecca? Regalberto?
All right, good. All right,
so let's move on then. Um.
So we're gonna talk about building a
backlog here.
So the the idea is here we want to be
able to identify, you know,
technical debt. You know, you can make,
we can make, you know,
have a scenario where you've been given
this.
Code base to to inspect and you need to
to advise you know the organization about
the the quality of the code base.
You want to be able to identify you know
what technical debt that that you would
be accumulating if you took on this
application.
So you want to be able to identify what
issues it has in the code base.
We also want to automate the creation of
those GitHub issues so that you can build
a backlog that that you can then use to
essentially build a a a a plan for
actually addressing the the technical
debt.
That that's like this in that code base.
Peter, did you have something?
Oh, sorry,
I was didn't realize I was not muted.
All right,
so so when we're talking about
identifying technical debt, yeah,
I can help us without, you know,
looking for outdated coding patterns and
or coding styles,
looking for high complexity,
duplicate logic, missing tests,
security vulnerabilities,
architectural drift.
And the the the main benefits are is that
we can rediscover this technical debt
very quickly.
We can have more consistent
classification of the debt of the
technical debt when we create the issues
and we can prioritize modernization,
create a prioritize modernization,
modernization roadmap, roadmap.
That can actually help us then move this
through our change control process in
order for us to get these items addressed.
So our next exercise is that we want to
take a look at the at building a backlog
and and and going about see if we can
create issues in in GitHub to.
Actually document exactly what we find
and when we're doing this exploration of
this new code base and and then we can
use that to help us to do a
prioritization,
trying to evaluate what the impact of
each of these issues are versus the
amount of effort it's going to require.
To to do that.
So we we we talked about a number of
tools yesterday to do this kind of work.
There's also in the AI assisted software
development repository some additional
prompts that you might want to take
advantage of.
That will help you identify.
Technical debt that you that we might
want to try to address.
So let's go ahead and give this a go and
see if we can get some issues created and
and and talk about that process.
Let me know if if you're having problems
getting started.
Um.
So let me bring up chat. See,
there's a message.
Yeah,
so you're if you're running a version of
Visual Studio code that's not 1.109.2,
you should update your VS code because
there's I think there's an
incompatibility between.
Older versions of US code that are not
the most current one and copilot.
I ran into this last night and I needed
to update to the 109.
2 version in order for us in order for me
to actually.
Work with a copilot again.
So.
Right, right.
They they they made a change in the API
that required an update to Visual Studio
code in order for it to work with the
back end API.
All right.
Raise your hand if you have any questions.
Do you have the prompts to creating it
into a GitHub issue? Um.
Um.
Yeah, basically, yeah.
What I did yesterday was basically added
on to the end of the the prompt to to
create GitHub issues for the findings.
You could also, if you don't,
if you're having issues actually
interacting with GitHub and creating the
issues,
you can just have them created in a file
in a in a folder and and that would
suffice. It wouldn't.
You wouldn't actually have to go through
and.
Troubleshoot any GitHub interactions.
You can, you know, figure that out later.
But it's nice to be able to see the
issues automatically get posted into into
GitHub.
And this is the one of the reasons why we
wanted to do a fork instead of a a clone
in that you all get each get your own
repository and you get to create your own
backlog.
So this doesn't have any in the
instruction file,
so if we want we would wanna move them in
so we have something.
Yes,
that would you know that would be the,
you know as we discussed yesterday,
that's kind of the first things that we
want to do is to to to not only bring in
the instruction files from our our, our,
our core instruction files from our,
you know our shared repository.
But you, yeah,
you may want to build new instruction
files for the technologies that are being
used and so that you can, you know,
have a broader range of of of things that
you're trying to evaluate.
Yeah,
so this is an exercise that is a bit
closer to a real world scenario.
Hi John,
I'm I'm actually having a problem.
Yes.
I actually didn't fork it initially,
I just cloned it.
But when I try to fork it from the the
GitHub website,
it's saying it cannot fork because the
repository is outside of my enterprise.
Companies account.
Which?
The fork button is disabled and when I
hover over it, it says cannot fork.
OK.
I can give a screenshot of it.
Do you does it show a drop down for your
username?
Because you could you could on mine.
I could choose either my my myself,
you know like to have it fork to my
profile.
Or you can have it forked here to an org
that you're in.
Uh,
is this the drop down on the word fork
itself?
Uh, I don't remember,
but it it it's when you go forward.
Because so that that doesn't give me any
options.
It doesn't give me any options when I
drop that down.
But let let me just at least show the
screenshot that I was talking about that
I'm having problems with.
I I have the same issue with my GitHub
enterprise through work,
but I so I had to switch to my personal
GitHub in order to clone it.
Oh, I don't have a personal one.
Oh, you know what? I might.
I'm on my enterprise with my personal one,
so that's probably why I could see both.
OK, alright.
We'll work on creating a personal account.
Thanks.
All right.
I'm not sure if I missed something,
but um,
I've been given what issues to create,
but Copilot's not creating anything for
me in GitHub.
Um.
Does is it creating anything?
Is it what you see output in the just in
the chat window?
It's just output in the chat window. Yeah,
issue #1, issue #2.
OK,
do you have to do a prompt that says that
you know?
Help me. Help me create these.
Help me post these issues to GitHub.
OK.
What does it return?
OK, I'll try that.
I I did tell it in the original prompt to
create GitHub issues for any that was
found, but it didn't.
Right. All right.
It ignored that prompt.
Yeah, right.
So that's we can troubleshoot it that way.
It may be that the.
That we have to log into.
There's some commands that we have to do.
I think with GitHub to actually get it to
to log into the the GitHub account.
So let me let me post those.
Yeah, try uh, try this.
John, when you have a second,
can you switch back to, uh,
the instructions for the exercise?
Yep, will do.
Thank you.
There you go.
Alright, I'm gonna switch back.
Let me know if you need to see it again.
Yeah,
can you go back again and I'll just take
a quick screenshot.
There you go.
Got it. Thanks.
Sure.
So if you do a GitHub auth status,
it should tell you if you're logged into
GitHub. It's the GitHub CLI.
With that you can use GitHub Auth login
and it will help you log into GitHub and
then that should allow you to communicate.
Hey, John, do you know? Go ahead.
Yeah, I've I'm sorry,
I'm just going to comment on that.
I've I've just explicitly asked Copilot
then to use certain it's a proper CLI
commands for GitHub and now it looks like
it might be doing it.
OK.
Don, I was gonna ask you,
do you know if Azure DevOps has a client
like this?
Or is it just GitHub and is Microsoft
migrating everything to GitHub and?
Some setting Azure DevOps in the future
to 'cause this type of automation is
great, right?
Like I wanna use this for sure.
Yeah, if we'd look for GitHub.
Copilot.
Uh, Azure.
Yeah, Copilot for Azure.
Yeah.
There probably is. Yeah, I see that.
There it is.
So here's the CLI extension.
There was another one that I posted in
Mhm.
the repo,
which is I'm not seeing in this list at
the moment.
But there's there's another one that's by
Microsoft that I don't see it in the list
at the moment.
OK, yeah, there probably is.
Or just use GitHub instead of DevOps.
Well, there's always that option, right?
Right.
You know from you know I don't know any I
I I have I don't really have any insight
into what Microsoft's road plans are so
but I had heard in the past that.
They were favoring GitHub over Azure
DevOps.
Yeah, I I've heard that too, actually.
Long term, I think that's the plan,
which makes sense.
Let me go to that repo.
Here is the one from Microsoft.
And.
I think this is the one to use.
It's got 5000 downloads and a 4 1/2 star
rating where everything else is a much
less.
And yeah, I'm gonna screenshot that.
Thanks.
Sure.
So raise your hand if you need more time
and.
A quick question.
Visual Studio question I guess.
OK.
I'm getting a link to enable shell
integration when I already have shell
integration enabled.
I don't know if there's a specific thing
OK.
for copilot that needs to be enabled.
But I'm looking at my settings and shell
integration is enabled.
OK, you know, have you tried asking?
A copilot to explain that issue or help
you fix it.
I I'll do that now.
It's not something I've seen.
So anybody discover anything in
interesting in their explore exploration
of this code base?
Authentication.
Yeah.
What about authentication?
Well,
just that you've added JWT off to the API
itself.
So in order to interact with that API,
we have to have a token,
presumably pass a token in the header.
Swagger.
Talking about the Um blog service, right?
Yes.
OK.
Yeah,
it should be the the AIA AIASD Brownfield
repo.
Yeah.
Oh, it's just the API,
so I maybe we'll be building the UI for
it or something.
Yeah, we can do that.
You.
Tests 2.
What was that?
Don't have any tests yet, so.
Oh.
Just a heads up,
issues were disabled on my repo by
default,
so that that prevented me from creating
Yeah.
issues. Just warning everyone.
Yes, I'm here.
Was that something that was supposed to
be added on the personal access token?
No, it's a setting for your repo.
So if you if you go to the settings in
Oh.
your repo,
you should be able to turn that on.
OK.
What setting is that? Uh?
Creating issues.
Yeah.
The issues which is it's called issues,
but I you know what I told Copilot
explicitly to create the ticket remotely
and it said issues are disabled.
Do you want me to enable them?
Hey John, I decided to do some experiment.
So like I I remember yesterday we were
Yeah.
talking about prompt files and I wasn't
familiar with that,
you know that type of technique.
So like I I decided instead of just
OK.
asking it for a report,
I told it to create a prompt for the
report.
And then that way,
because it seems like something you would
OK.
want to run, you know, repeatedly, right?
Would that be?
Yeah.
Is that like a good use case for creating
the prompt file?
Like something you want to repeat over
and over again?
Yeah, yeah, that's a that's a good.
That's exactly what they're designed to
do is to encapsulate this into a file so
that you can reuse them in different
projects or.
Or just rely. Yeah,
like basically if you don't like how it
Or just run, run.
like on mine it didn't do,
it didn't say anything about unit test
coverage. If I didn't like that,
I could change that prompt file, right?
And then that way it's always gonna
behave.
The way I, you know,
like I expect it to behave, right?
That's right. That's right. So yeah,
so by encapsulating into a prompt file,
you can not only remember what you
actually did at the time to produce those
the backlog originally,
but you could actually reuse it and run
it on an occasion.
You would probably want to add things to
that prompt file to to not create any
duplicate issues.
Which might be a little bit of a
challenge for to to be able to identify
it,
but if it's using the same logic in your
prompt file,
then it it should be able to do a decent
job of identifying that that this is the
same issue as something that was created
earlier and so I won't go ahead and do
that right.
All right. So how are we doing on this?
I see two people with their hands up.
Are you just trying to finish up or do
you have a question?
I'm still, yeah,
I I ended up creating an instruction file
Find us in the shop.
Uh.
for doing a code base analysis and that
took a while and now that's running.
OK.
But but don't let me hold things up,
it's just running.
All right.
So how many issues have we found so far?
The code looks pretty good,
it's just missing tests basically.
Yeah,
mine's having a lot of trouble uploading
the issues,
so I'm just having it continuously debug
it.
Yeah, and if you, you know you can just,
you know,
create them as files in a folder and
that'll do for now.
We're on GitHub. Do you see the issues?
Sorry, I don't see it.
The code pull request agents, actions,
projects.
If you're,
you can go to General and Scroll down.
There's a tick box for issues in the
settings for your repo.
Yeah, yeah,
I did that and I and I had it and I had a
That's where I found it.
VS code create an issue, but I sorry,
I don't use GitHub really.
I don't see where the issues are in my
repo.
It seems to take a while to enable issues
because I'm still not able to to do
anything even though I've enabled issues
on the repo.
And Dan, if if you enable it and refresh,
you should across your top navigation bar
But.
you should see code issues,
pull request actions.
Oh, I see it now. I see it now. Thanks.
OK.
But I mostly use Azure Dev apps,
so there's only issues like you know,
in Azure Dev apps there's features,
there's PB is, there's tasks,
there's bugs.
But in GitHub there's only issues, right?
Right.
Right, that's that's right.
You you can tag them as being bugs or or
the like,
but they're all issues inherently.
You know, I haven't used it,
but that that extension I showed you.
Um.
Has the ability to create issues among
other things.
So you so you should be able to with that
tool say this is a this is a bug or this
is a this is a feature or or or however
you want to do this when Azure in Azure
DevOps.
Yeah.
So you can essentially apply the same
same ideas,
the same same concepts and techniques,
but just use a different tool to do the
work.
Gotcha. OK, thanks. Yeah,
I was able to create an issue from VS
code, so I I lowered my end.
I think I was the last one.
All right, great.
So this is something that we can,
you know, continue to refine.
But what we wanted to do is to try to do
something that establish this backlog and
the the idea is if we looked at the
prompts in the.
In the folder,
there's a a number of different prompts
here that we could have used to, you know,
do a code base review.
Right, so we could say, um,
let me open this up.
So this does this code base versus
instruction audit Uh prompt.
Yeah.
Um.
All right,
here's one for creating issues for dead
code, creating issues for found bugs.
And things like that. Security,
a security audit, looking for that,
looking for test gaps.
Yes.
All of these prompts would would help us
identify issues that goes into our go
into our backlog.
So in a matter of you know an hour or or
so by running these prompts you could you
know for a brand new code base establish
a.
Fairly comprehensive backlog of things
that needs to be done and then the next
part was to evaluate it in terms of.
In terms of the the impact of the issue
versus the the amount of effort involved,
so you could ask,
you could ask AI to to examine the issues
in the in the backlog and prioritize them
based on the the amount of effort.
Put in the the the actual impact to the
so that you you could prioritize the
things that are most important to fix
first.
You can also include in a in a prompt
like that to.
Consider the the dependencies of you know
one issue on one issue on another so that
you're doing the things that are that are
have depend things that are depended on
1st as so that you can get that work
accomplished sooner.
So this whole, this whole,
this whole part of it,
what I think is really powerful and
something I've used quite a bit is that
by establishing that backlog,
you now raise the visibility of all of
the technical debt to the rest of the
team and the organisation.
Um and.
What I think what you're going to find is
that the real bottleneck now becomes not
the actual fixing of the issues,
because we can do that fairly simply and
very quickly using a I.
It's going to be the prioritization of
the of the work as well as the reviewing
of the work once you're complete in which
the.
What's AI has completed doing the the
remediation.
So that's that becomes where where most
of the time is in terms of fixing or the
technical data is going to be wrapped up.
So you could identify all these items in
the backlog,
but you still need to get it to your your.
Software development process to to get it
approved for for for fixing.
I mean you need to review these these
these issues just to make sure that
they're accurate and that there is that
something hasn't slipped through the A I
that's that would that be incorrect or
something they shouldn't be doing.
You also need to evaluate what the what
the recommended fixes are to make sure
that you agree with those fixes.
But once you've once you've done that,
you know you can then just hand an issue
off to a a copilot and say.
Go ahead and address this issue.
Which is pretty simple.
So this is still thinking,
so I'm looking to create some identify
some issues of this.
And that'll give us some backlog to work
on.
All right.
Any questions on this exercise or?
I got a question about those prompts.
Are are you gonna add those to the repo
Hey.
'cause they're not in there yet, right?
Or or?
They're not in your repo,
but they're in the they're in the A I
assisted software development repo.
So I just copied them from 1 folder to
the next. I can show you what I did there.
All right, so.
Oh,
I didn't see them in that folder 'cause I
pulled latest this morning.
Did you just add them?
So what I.
Yes.
Into the AI assisted software development.
Yeah. Oh, this is the topic as well. OK,
I was looking at the one from the first
Um.
M.
No, no, this is this.
So this this repo is kind of like your
day. OK.
toolkit that you're getting from this
course of things that I've created and
used over the over the, you know,
over time that has helped me out and that
you might find some value in.
So you know,
we talked about how to share these
between between projects.
Right now we're doing the a syncing type
of approach where we're just copying the
files over from one repo into the next.
You know they're.
We talked about other ways using the
co-pody setting files and sub repos in
order for us to share share these
instruction files from a central location
and and and and keep control over them.
We you know if you work in a lot of
projects replicating these among we also
talked about using a like an
organizational level instruction file
which would be I I think ideal for for
for many of these types of.
Instruction files to be put and shared
across multiple repos within an
organization.
So anyway, yeah, go ahead.
Hey, John, this.
Is there? Is there some?
Limitation to the number of instruction
files that you can create and use like.
Can you just go? I mean, you know,
is there a naming convention that copilot
knows to look for specific instruction
files to apply under certain scenarios?
Um.
You can.
Well, one you can.
You can refer to them explicitly in your
prompts,
or you can refer them to them explicitly
Right.
in your prompt files that you want to
incorporate these particular instruction
Mm.
files. What I'll talk about tomorrow is.
How to use agents to encapsulate much of
this information in terms of the
instruction files and be more precise
about what is actually included and you
can make that apply to a multiple prompts
or that you're that you're executing.
By invoking a a custom agent to to to
control that,
there's also in prom files the ability to
say that this applies to certain file
extensions and and there's other patterns
that you can use that.
Where you can express how that
instruction file gets utilized and you
can, as I mentioned yesterday,
you can also put them in a specific
folder. So we're to look at our.
Our our implementation here where we have
a controllers folder,
you could put an instruction file in this
folder that would only apply to the the
the content of that folder.
So but your the answer to your question
is yeah there is a finite limit in this
in that if you you know.
If we looked at our diagnostics,
we can see that we're bringing in quite a
few.
And instruction files.
Mhm.
But.
Um.
Yeah.
In our context and so your limit is going
to be eventually that you're going to run
out of your your support in your context
window for all of these all of this
content because it's all it's all being
loaded automatically for you.
And so that's what I want to talk about a
little tomorrow is OK, how do we.
How do we focus this?
How to provide more focus to this so that
we're not bringing everything in all the
time, right? But yeah,
there is a limit and you have to manage
that. You want to use the tools down here.
Hmm.
To see how much of the context window
you're how many.
What you're seeing and you can also use
this icon over here to show here like
like system instructions. These are.
Basically what all these files when we
noticing if we as we've gone through and
building out more and more instruction
files, this number has been going up.
You know it started out at like 5% and
now it's a third of our context windows
is just being consumed by.
The instruction files that we have told
it that if we want to use.
And so you can see here that I'm starting
to get, you know,
68% of my context window.
When it starts to get to farther here,
it'll start changing the UI to try to
warn you that you're starting to exceed
your context window.
OK.
Other questions?
And I think that's the big.
I have a question so I.
Oops, raise your hand please.
That way we can do this.
Mm.
Yeah, go ahead.
Well, I've you can go ahead.
I've asked a lot of questions,
OK. I was, yeah, I was just gonna.
I was just gonna continue on with that
so you please go. I'll raise it.
one, John. Like, you know, I mean, we're.
One of the goals for myself and my
teammates who are attending this class
with you is to be able to take this
knowledge back to our organization and
share it.
And one of the biggest takeaways that
I've captured so far is.
You know, from an enterprise perspective,
creating prompt files,
creating instruction files,
how to use them properly,
essentially how to treat copilot as a
team member, right? And and you know,
Right.
so there's myself and two other
colleagues are here from our company,
right? And we're each.
Leaders on our own teams and so you know
my take away is,
is that you know I think that on my team
specifically we'll be investing in a a
set of instruction and prompt files for
my team for the type of software that we
build and and.
And you know,
I think the other team members will
probably do that for their teams in their
repositories as well.
And then I think we want to understand
how we can take that to the organization
level.
How can we define standards and you know
all of the all of the things right and
and use copilot.
Right.
And treat Copilot as a team member going
forward, right?
I mean that that's the huge,
that's the big take away that I'm getting
so far from all of this.
Yeah,
I think that's that's really what we're
trying to accomplish in this course is to
give you the the the skills that you need
in order to be able to accomplish that.
And that's where when we get into agents
tomorrow,
those are the next big piece that's
missing out of that.
That effort, right?
So you know the the the chat modes
essentially allow us to wrap up these
instruction files and these prompt files
and and essentially create not just one
AI team member.
But a whole range of them that we can
invoke on a on a case by case,
Mhm.
task by task basis and say OK,
I want to have a a chat mode or a agent
OK.
that is an expert in software
requirements.
And use that when I am when I'm managing
my backlog or dealing with how to define
new requirements for a new feature or the
like. I can use that one.
And I can even have it, you know.
So when I'm doing these kind of backlog
grooming sessions or these these sessions
that I'm going through and scoring the
code base,
I could have one agent that really
understands C# code very well and is
focused on that.
Actually create the the first draft of a
a of an issue from a technical
perspective,
but then the a more business analyst
looks at it in terms of prioritization
and organization and trying to to build a
plan for actually implementing it.
Things like that.
Yeah, yeah.
All right, Dan, you had a question.
Yeah,
so I assigned one of the issues to A to
copilot and I see it made a pull request
and it's just it just has one commit.
It just says initial plan. Oh,
I think now I think it has a second
commit.
Is there a way to see it like as it's
working?
You know while if you assign something to
copilot,
is there a way to kind of see you know
like if you're in VS code you can kind of
see it thinking and doing its thing and
all that stuff like when you when you
start it from the website to to assign it.
Yeah, there is. You can actually,
you know view the session that it's using
on the on the back end and that will show
you,
you know where it stands currently in the
process as well as what it's done so far.
So if you sign an issue to the to copilot
there,
the other thing that you should probably
do is.
Is which I I think I've mentioned,
but it's something to re-emphasize is
that you can go into your settings and
you can turn on copilot code reviews and
what that will do is anytime you create a
a a pull request.
Copilot will automatically assign itself
as a reviewer of that pull request and
then evaluate, you know,
go ahead and look for issues and add add
those things that it finds.
To the comments of the of the pull
request and that gives you the the
ability to you know address them directly
which sometimes it can do that or take
what it what it's recommending and
implement it your yourself and then.
Push push that change back into that same
pull request and have that be reviewed
again.
So you'll need to have a a a paid
subscription to do that, but.
But it's yeah,
that's a a nice way to to also get work
done.
But yeah, you can,
you can view the session and see that and
we might be able to,
I might be able to demonstrate that a
So.
little bit later.
OK, yeah,
I think in the settings under Copilot
there's code review and it says create a
rule set.
So if I do that then it should then
automatically do code reviews and any
pull requests.
Yes,
if you turn on the the code reviews in
the copilot section of the settings that
that will enable that feature and you
Yeah, OK.
should be able to then any pull request
you you take create will get that code
review.
And that's a a good first start of it.
One of the things that I've done is um.
Is asked two different models to to
evaluate the the same code base.
The reason for that is that it tend that
it tends to eliminate the bias in one
model.
By using one model,
and I mentioned this the other day that
the models have a certain affinity for
the code that they write.
So if you asked it to compare,
you know code written by one model versus
versus another model.
And then you ask one of those two models
to review the code base,
it will tend to prefer the code that was
created by it.
And that's I think that makes a certain
amount of sense because you know it has a
certain amount of training data,
it understands a certain way the code
should be written.
It's been tweaked by the providers of the
of the model for particular to have
particular characteristics,
so it will recognize its code and more
readily than it would recognize another
implementation because of those
differences.
So using multiple models to do code
reviews and or particularly having a
review being done by a different model
than the what the code is.
Can be a good can be a good idea and you
can even go as far as say I want to have
three different models do it and I want
them to see if any of the two models
agree that the code is doesn't require
any significant changes and if they.
If they both agree, then you can,
or two of the three agree.
You can assume that that that you're
essentially eliminated any bias.
You're getting a good signal that the
code is ready for a human review at that
point.
So you have to do that sort of manually,
right?
You just in VS code you make a new
session,
pick a new model and then just ask it to
review the code. Is that?
Yeah,
that's pretty much how you go about doing
it. You put, you know,
you what I've done in the past is create.
Separate branches for each of the
evaluations and then ask AI to compare
them and and and tell and report with the
pros and cons of each implementation or
or each review is and and.
And then you could essentially use the
result of that to decide what your,
you know,
which course you want to take Peter.
Hey John,
I just wanna circle back around and talk.
You were talking about,
you know when we were talking about
prompt files and instruction files,
you know and and getting granular and
defining the different domains for those,
right.
I wanna make sure that that's that I
understood that correctly that you know
that kind of the.
To be able to be, you know,
setting standards for C# or C++ or unit
testing or refactoring or architecture,
those are all kind of different top level
domains that we would want to define
prompt and instruction files for, correct?
That's correct.
And that's where that's where the the
So it's OK.
agents or chat modes come into play is
that you can actually say I want to
create an agent that is a let's use a
solutions architect.
And you can say that this solution
architect is an expert in these kinds of
OK.
these areas of software development
specifically and and you can define
Mhm, Yep.
commands that are associated with that
particular agent.
And have those commands execute a prompt
that is then targeted towards the that
particular functionality, right?
So so that that give that gives you the
Right.
ability to kind of craft these.
Teammates that you're going to create
these AI teammates that are experts in
certain aspects of the software
development process and then you can just
Mm.
go in and use your agent here.
You can see here that I've got a number
of them defined and.
Gotcha. Gotcha.
Here's one that's a project expert, right?
So here's one that's an expert in git.
Oh yeah.
So if you're having a git issue,
you can you can actually select this and
then you can have that that git expert
then be the the be the agent that
actually first processes that prompt.
And then whatever expertise that you've
defined within that,
that chat mode or agent,
then it gets put into the context and
then it's used and it's really a way of
of focusing the context down to.
A very specific set of skills that are
targeted for a specific thing, you know?
Yes.
Yeah.
And once you get accustomed to saying, OK,
I I should always be using one of these,
Right. Did you?
right?
I shouldn't be doing any work alone, yeah.
Did you say we were gonna get into that
tomorrow? Defining this? OK, good.
Yeah, yeah, right.
We'll talk about creating many of these
or how to go create new ones or and look
at them tomorrow.
Cool.
Awesome.
OK,
so this is Ron is identified just to
running that one prompt that there's a a
secret that's been exposed.
It's not using HTTPS missing a AI logs.
I was expecting to see those there's.
No test coverage, right.
So no CICD pipeline.
So these are all important things that we
would probably want to probably want to
address. So it's.
So if somebody came to us and said here,
take a look at this code base and tell us
whether it's worthwhile enhancing this
code base or fixing it or or the like,
right?
We could then say something like uh.
Uh, prioritize.
Um, these issues?
Uh, impact.
Versus.
Approved.
All right.
So it's going to go ahead and do that.
And we could then ask it to to to go
ahead and update the.
The issues in GitHub with this with the
with this particular priority.
And now we've we've moved closer to.
I should probably use a different agent
for this.
But we'll let it go.
So anyway,
so this allows us to essentially put into
this backlog and this is the thing that
you know this section is really trying to
drive for is that to try to make the
technical debt that you that you see in
your project that A I is able to identify
make that visible to the rest of the
organization so that it can be
prioritized.
And then you can argue that, look,
A I can can help us pay down a good deal
of this technical debt,
particularly if you start with the things
that are have the largest impact and the
the the least amount of effort and the
least amount of introducing the least
amount of risk into the process.
You can then start to pay down that
technical debt fairly quickly and get
yourself into a much more Evergreen state
without having to spend a lot of,
you know, human resources to actually,
you know,
figure out what needs to be done and
create a.
Implementations for that.
The other thing that you can do with with
many of these issues is or or or the like
is you can ask a I to propose how would
we go about implementing a a a solution.
So,
so that way you can actually get a a a
sense of what it would actually do and
you can then evaluate whether that makes
sense or not.
So here it's produced a phase zero
security of an infinite amount of return
on investment.
So when did it create it, change the file.
So here is our.
Prioritization matrix.
So one thing we could add to our
instruction file is that whenever you're
creating a diagram in the in a markdown
file to use Mermaid.
And here we can see all of the issues and
they're all prioritized.
All right, questions there?
All right,
then let's see where we stand here.
So we've done this, built this backlog.
We have,
so we now have some things that we're
targeting.
So moving on to just building safety Nets
for projecting these brownfield databases,
leveraging those AI code reviews,
we've talked about some of this effective
human code reviews.
So we'll talk a bit about that in the
role of test automation.
So in terms of protecting those
brownfield code bases,
we want to preserve existing behavior
until it's intentionally changed.
So the idea here is that we want to have
a test suite that will.
Will constantly reassure us that that we
haven't broken anything in the production
system.
We'll talk a a bit more about achieving
that in in a second,
but we but it's really important that we
have some way to evaluate that that
doesn't require.
A great deal of human intervention in
order to be able to make that
determination.
We also want to avoid large risky
refactors.
We want to break things down into small
pieces that can be easily verified and
deployed so we can and and so we can move.
Quickly and get things out into
production faster.
We can use feature flags to actually hide
some of that behaviour if we if it's not
quite ready to be exposed to users,
but still can be deployed to production.
You could use use incremental
modernization where we're we're just
making we're making a slow steady stream
of improvements over time and not making
anything that's too too too big or too
too risky.
Maintain the architectural boundaries.
This is kind of goes with the the
discussion of scenes yesterday where
we're breaking up the the code base into
areas that that are well isolated and
decoupled so that they can be
independently tested.
And we want to document all that AIS to
change and that's where our AI logs come
to play and and some of this metadata.
So it's important because you know the
thing about brownfield development is
that these systems are currently running
the business and the what we don't want
is to have our A I introduce something
into the.
Those systems that would cause other
people to question our ability to
effectively use this.
So we really want to build these safety
Nets for our own benefit so that we
understand and can control all of the
change that's going into the code base
from multiple different.
And sources and all that works well
together.
So so stability is is more important than
new things per se per SE.
But AI should give us the ability to to
to keep the the the the code base stable
while we're adding.
Either addressing technical data or
adding your features and they they they
reverse the fear and increase your
confidence right?
So by having having those protections you
you feel.
More at ease and more empowered to
actually make more significant changes to
the code base. So a a I code reviews.
We talked a bit about this,
about having that copilot do them.
You can also request more specific things
that you wanted to look at.
Just to the chat.
So this can do things like highlighting
risky changes, detecting missing tests.
This is some of the backlog grooming that
we talked about identifying architectural
violations. You can actually,
you can like I said,
actually have it proposed.
What it suggests an approach to to fixing
things and then you can then have it
suggest more than one way of addressing a
problem and you can choose between those.
And then of course it will help you by
surfacing potential regressions.
So this will provide us with faster
feedback loops,
more consistent review quality and an
earlier detection of of of drift.
So the idea here is that you know one of
the things that we have to keep in mind
is that.
But by using AI to generate more code
faster, we're creating,
I think 2 human backlogs that we have to
try to come up with strategies to address.
And the first,
the first one is on the front end before
the work is done.
In terms of the the the work reviewing
the the issues that we're creating to the
backlog and do all that that do the
backlog grooming work to prepare to make
sure that the organization is comfortable
moving forward with any particular piece
of work.
And then on the back back end,
it's after the AI has written the codes
to how to get it reviewed.
And if the and I guess my point is that
the if we're moving faster,
we're increasing the amount of work that
without that it has to be done otherwise
that human work becomes.
A a backlog that prevents us to from
actually moving as fast as we could and
if we can leverage AI to help us reduce
those the the backlog for those code
reviews, then that would be.
That would help us in in terms of
increasing our our our our the pace of
our our our change.
So then we go. So.
So the way that I think about it is I
want AI to review everything first and
until AI accept the accepts it as as a
valid change,
I don't want to have to deal with it.
I want that.
I only want to see things for.
My so I have a human view if it's already
passed one or more.
A I reviews and those A I reviews could
be targeted at specific areas.
You could have one that's reviewing the
documentation,
one that's reviewing the the the the
actual code implementation,
one is the impact on the architecture and
in conformance with standards and
practices.
All of these things could be different
types.
Of code reviews,
like you can do a security analysis.
All of these things can be done by AI,
at least at the initial level.
And then once it's passed all of those
reviews,
then I think we can take a look at it and
see, OK, they can then.
They're essentially in a position where
they're approving or not approving the
quality of those reviews.
So you're really looking at what the
intent was and is and is that intent
properly implemented?
In the code,
is it aligned to the architecture that
you're trying to implement?
Is the is the business logic validation
accurate and and is there any risk that's
that's being introduced as a as a part of
this change?
And ensuring that the changes are
incremental and and reversible are are
things that we can do as humans that that
that can over on top of what the A I are
in terms of their review.
So you want to keep these change sets
small because that makes it easier for
everybody.
To that to that's looking at it as ask
for context when it's missing.
So you know this is where you can
interrogate the A I about you know why
did it choose a particular implementation
pattern versus another and get and get a
better understanding.
About the what it how it interpreted the
intent that it was given.
And then you would, you know,
look at it with curiosity and and with
with skepticism. Because in in many cases,
in my experience is that anytime I ask A
I to do something,
it typically gives me more than what I
asked to ask it to do.
And in some cases that's a gold plating
and something I don't need.
And in other cases,
it's actually a really significant
improvement to what I would have done had
I been thinking about it only on my own.
All right.
Any questions so far on some of this
material?
So let's then talk about the test
automation, right?
So this gives us some behavioral
guarantees, some regression detection,
confidence for our modernization and then
some guard guardrails for the A I
assisted refactoring.
So we want you know all.
The many different types of tests that
we've all seen the you know the the the
pyramid of testing where you have more
unit tests than you have integration test
and then you have more integration tests
than you would have end to end behavioral
tests.
So you and then you want to have tests
that are are looking at basically at what
your APIAPI contracts are and and
essentially evaluating in in many
different ways and and this is another
factor that you can build up.
With AI's help,
a fairly comprehensive suite of tests
that perform many different kinds of
operation tests automation against it,
you know,
going into load testing and performance
testing and and the like.
So there's many different ways that we
can build a test.
Suite that has a great deal of robustness
and every time we add more testing to
that process,
we increase our level of confidence
because remember that one heuristic is
that you know if all the test automation
passes.
Is how comfortable do you feel about
releasing that to production in a in a
brownfield environment?
There's there's a risk associated with
every deployment,
and you want to make sure that you're in
a position that you feel comfortable
going in and that if there's an issue
that shows up,
you can easily get back to a unknown.
Good state so that there's there's no no
issues in in production that will cause a
lot of hand wringing about the processes
that we're using.
Feature flags are are a great tool for
that because you can actually do what are
called Canary releases where you actually
roll this out to a small subset of the
user base so that only a certain few
people are affected by the initial
implementation.
And then if that goes well,
you can then slowly increase the number
of users that are are are available to
actually invoke those change or take
advantage of those changes and and that
way if there is a a a risk of.
Of the that you're going to introduce
something into production that would
cause a problem that you're you're not
affecting the entire code base user base,
you're just affecting.
Essentially you would start with your
your most forgiving.
User base that are most willing to give
you positive feedback about what those
changes are, how how they're implemented,
and then take advantage of that feedback
to either turn off a feature flag or and
make some additional modifications before
you make it more widely available.
So let's let's take a look at target
since we have no test in this in this in
this project.
So it's a a good a good target for this
kind of activity.
Let's go ahead and you know.
And start to ask AI,
you know what kinds of tests would it,
what does it,
does it want to or does it think that we
should be implementing and then start to
go ahead and and see if we can implement
some of those tests.
Let's let's ask you about you know how
we're doing in terms of code coverage and
it could tell us how much you know where
areas that need additional test coverage
are reside and we can actually then
target the ones that that have the the
the poor.
Test coverage,
we can also ask it to prioritize the test
that we should implement to the ones that
would have the biggest impact.
So that you know basically things that
are most critical to the functioning of
the application,
we can make sure that those are well
tested.
1st and and as I said earlier,
if you have a very large code base that
doesn't have the the test coverage that
you would like,
you can take an approach where you you
add the test coverage just in just in
front of.
The areas that you're making
modifications to so that those areas that
you're going to change have good test
coverage before you actually implementing
any modifications into the system. Also,
let's go ahead and take some time to ask
AI to.
Help us write some tests and let's see
how much we can, how much test coverage.
That we see.
So let's raise our hands to start the
exercise and lower that when we finish
and then why don't you post into chat the
the percentage of code cover coverage
that you were able to achieve as a result
of adding these additional tests.
So.
Just a quick question,
are we all running on copilot free 'cause
I've reached my Max?
Well then you just need to switch to the
free models and use the free models until
for the rest of the course you may not
get, you may not get as much.
OK.
You know, you're using an older model,
but they should be so perfectly
functional for what we're trying to do.
I think if you sign up you get one month
free, right?
Without, I mean,
you have to put down your credit card
information,
but I think the first month is free.
At least that's what it said to me when I
signed up.
Yeah, I I had used that up last month.
They won't give you another one,
Oh, OK.
unfortunately. Thanks, Will.
OK.
Yeah,
well I've I've had that same problem.
I started with the free one and then ran
out of tokens and then I purchased the
the the pro version and ran out of those
tokens and then.
So far on the Pro Plus version for $40 a
month,
I've I've yet to see that issue come up.
So you know my perspective on it is you
know to spend $40 a month for a tool that
provides this amount of value is.
I think certainly well worth the the
money,
and if you're if you're a mechanic and
having to buy your own tools,
it would cost you a lot more than that.
Can I ask you a question about the
feature flags?
Yeah.
I mean that also has risk too because I
mean it is change code,
we're just trying to turn it off or or
and then what just have some some users
turned on by a by a hidden app setting or
something like this or?
Well, yeah,
there's a there's a whole number of
different frameworks that you can
leverage and and and third party services
that you can leverage in Azure.
There's a configuration service that that
can that can help you with feature flags.
Ideally you want the setting of those of
those of those flags.
To be external to the code base so that
you can change them on the fly and have
the application recognize that
configuration change in some fashion.
So if you are looking to implement this I
would I would research what those.
Frameworks that are available are and
then you know choose something that's
that meets your needs.
But but you know there you'll you'll have
a lot of options for that.
OK. Thanks.
It'll be copied that you have the folder
over from the other repo of this one.
Is that what you did, John?
Yeah,
what I did was basically go into File
Explorer.
Yeah.
I think it's here. I opened up.
Here's the AI assistant one,
which is the source of truth.
Here's the project.
OK.
I just grabbed the whole GitHub folder
here and dragged it into the project.
Yep. OK, cool.
OK.
John,
could you share the prompt you used to do
that plan?
Yeah, sure.
What the spelling error or?
Oh yeah, that's OK.
I'll be happy from there.
Understand.
No.
It.
Yeah.
Everyone still working on it?
If you're if you're finished,
just lower your hand.
Hey, John.
Yeah.
So having never used Visual Studio Code
or GitHub before,
like just pressing through the tools is
is plenty of challenge,
but you know I'm doing the best I can and
for example I prompted for you know
architectural constraints in the project
and and they gave me a list just in the
the prompt response.
Yeah.
And like I say,
just kind of struggling with the tools.
I miss a whole lot of what you say,
but is is is there a better way?
Like should this be captured maybe is
like have it converted to markdown and
put it in a directory within the project
or what?
What do you suggest doing with these
architectural constraints?
Turn turn them into tickets?
Well,
if they're if they're actionable
modifications,
then I say let's surface them as as
tickets and that way they can be
prioritized and you know and we we can
work on them, right.
So that would be that would be what I
would do with them if I was working in a.
If this was a a project that I was
participating in is I want to make sure
that the rest of the team knew that the
application had these had these these
these particular things and then you can
argue for you know dispense you know some
a I time on let's implement these
modifications.
Right, so you know,
but I chose to equated this test plan
automation and I chose to create it as a
markdown file and put it in a docs folder,
which you can see here is what it's done.
And so now I've captured that plan and
I'm then asking it to go ahead and.
Start to implement some,
start to take some immediate actions on
try to establish a a a a a test framework
and start to write some tests.
I see. All right. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Anybody stuck on something that I can
help with?
No,
I guess I'm just moving a little bit
slower, but we can move on.
Yeah, I'll give you a couple more minutes.
So should we have it implement some of
them or is it just mainly just to to to
Yeah, yes. Go ahead and go ahead and,
yeah,
look at the report?
go ahead and get as far into it as you
can. Um.
And what?
Because what I'll do next is I'm going to
review the plan that I created and we can
just you see, you know.
What the AI would expect us to is
expecting us to do.
All right, so um.
So I cheated a little bit, I actually.
Invoked the.
Dev test engineer.
Chat mode that we'll talk about tomorrow
and then I asked it to to create a a a
test automation plan for this for the
project and you can see that as it's
typical.
It gives you more than you expect when
you ask it,
when you make a essentially a very
generic request.
Unless you say I only wanted something,
a specific type of information,
it's going to give you everything it
thinks it need it would need.
So it basically has an analysis of the
project,
which is just an overview of the
technology stack,
the project structure and then you can
see here that it has high value test
areas,
things that are critical in terms of
testing or authentication and controllers
and the service layer.
And then the auto map or profiles and
exception handling are are considered
high value targets.
So we would have here is our our pyramid
where we were talking about end to end
tests or 10% of the of the test load
integration test would be 30% then unit
test would be 60%.
So here are the test categories of what
and what tests.
That it's expecting to see.
Well integration tests it it's it's it's
it's proposing that we create and what
those any tests would be.
Here is the test project structure and so
that it's expecting to build out a pretty
comprehensive structure for those tests.
What new get packages we need to to
install in order for us to be able to run
the tests,
the quality metrics and coverage goals
and 90% coverage or greater for our core
business logic.
The controllers are 85 percent,
100% for the auto mapper and acceptance
handlers, so.
Go shooting for a a goal of 80% or
greater code coverage.
What some of the key performance metrics
would should be a defect prevention
strategy, so functional testing,
non-functional testing,
performance testing,
load testing scenarios.
What tools suggesting that that we use
for that testing some performance
benchmarks?
An implementation road map.
So I think it's interesting here that the
road map is broken down into two weeks.
You know when I sometimes I see these
estimates,
I ask it how to how it actually
calculated.
The the the duration of the of these
phases.
And then here's the tasks that need to be
done and each week.
Then how we would integrate it into a
pipeline?
So the test will automatically be
executed. Confirmations on quality gates.
So coverage.
These are all the metrics that we want to
try to achieve.
Then some sample test example.
So basically templates for creating tests.
Controller tests should look like this
integration tests.
An end-to-end test.
So the the key point about if you
generate a document like this that you
you you need to essentially do a pretty
thorough review on it and and get some
get the team essentially to buy off on
this is the the approach particularly
looking at the test examples.
And because because those are gonna
govern actually the code that you see
generated.
So you want to make sure that you're
comfortable with the entire plan.
Uh,
before we actually move on to
implementation, but we're not going to.
Take that level of effort right now
because we don't really have the time to
do it. But it is something that for,
you know, with every generated artifact,
there's always a little tag that says
this could be wrong and that's and that's
always going to be true.
So we always want to make sure that.
We're approving of these,
a lot of this AI generated artifacts,
so so that we're comfortable that the
quality of the work and that we're
comfortable that we understand exactly
what the ASII is doing for us.
Mm.
All right. So any questions,
further questions on this, this activity?
I think I went through in the project and
had it.
Clear.
The first piece of this so it wants to.
It's creating some test utility files.
Looks like it's got a problem with the
build.
So,
so we can see here that it's this is I
think a fairly typical process and that
once we've created a plan and we say I
want to implement the immediate actions,
it will go through and and and start to
do some of that work but.
Um.
Yeah, sometimes we'll run into issues.
I find this also with test generation
that sometimes the 1st.
Attempt at a test doesn't succeed and for
whatever reason and it will need to to go
through and actually debug that process.
So it's still seeing a a bunch of errors
in the build.
So we'll let it continue to.
Turn on this technical piece. Yeah, Dan.
Yeah. So I just have a question about,
you know what, what it can generate.
So obviously unit tests,
it's really good at that.
But you know what about integration
testing end to end testing?
Is that something we want them to
integrate? Would they still be, you know,
quote UN quote unit tests,
but they're actually kind of run?
Differently or would they be like
separate applications? Or you know,
how do you distinguish the different
kinds of of tests like that?
Right.
I mean the the the primary difference
that I see in a unit test or and
integration test is that the unit tests
you know mock out or don't execute
anything that the the particular unit
that's under testing.
It calls out where a integration test
would.
So you're mostly in dealing with
integration tests like calling out to an
endpoint of an API and validating that
you get the response back that you want.
So that will require some some sort of
way of deploying that application,
either just running it locally or.
Running it in a in a deployed environment
and and in order to be able to do an end
testing you would have to do it.
You would most likely want to deploy it
into a into a a,
you know a temporary environment and then
execute it there.
But A I can help us with all those tests.
We can do so it it's it's it understands
you know all the major test frameworks
that we would want to be using.
And.
So it it can help us build up that test
suite and that you know,
you know that's I think as far as
broadfield development,
one of the major things that we get out
of using A I is that it helps us really
up our game in terms of our test
automation.
In terms of both the quality of the tests
that are executing and and the quantity
or coverage that we're able to achieve in
a very short period of time by just,
you know,
creating a valid test plan that makes
sense that when we go ahead and execute
against that test plan.
And then monitor our progress,
you know in terms of its ability to
evaluate the application as we go as we
move forward.
Okay, thanks.
Sure. Any other questions?
All right,
so a bit more on test automation and code
quality.
We talked quite a bit about AI assisted
test generation.
We can also do an intelligent enlisting
linting beyond static analysis.
This would you know what we would ask you
know questions of the A I about the the
coding having coding standards and
bouncing the A the code that we have
against some of those coding standards
you can as we see you can do help us with
the coverage analysis and the.
Ade the adequacy of our assessment and so
we can actually look at if we had
existing test,
it could look at the test and and pick
apart the test to see if it's actually
testing everything that it should be to
help us create those automated quality
gates through pipelines.
So we talked about that.
So in terms of generation,
we can see that we can deal with all
these different kinds of tests.
This samples as we said,
I just mentioned say helps us rapidly
expand our coverage and the and I said
the quality equals test and have it and
then apply consistent.
Structure and naming convention on on all
the the tests so that we can so that so
that everybody that's working the code
base understands how these tests are
built and and that can reduce the amount
of time it takes to come to come up to
speed on on a code base.
So intangibility you can do things like
looking for architectural violations,
you can look for anti-patterns,
unsafe refactors,
looking for missing documentation,
inconsistent naming and domain
terminology.
That's you know something that where you
can get a more semantic view of the your
of your code base versus just what the
the the code is there.
So this will go beyond just the syntax.
You can enforce architectural guard
guardrails.
And reduce your long-term technical debt
by making sure that you're any changes
that you make are are are consistent with
the instructions that we that we built.
So in in terms of coverage analysis,
it can help us evaluate the any look for
any coverage gaps, missing edge cases,
over testing of implementation details,
under testing of business logic,
looking for redundant or or or brittle
tests.
Which gives us more meaningful coverage
again we this is all about a signal
that's telling us what is what is the
current state of the the code base and is
it is it in a in a position where we feel
comfortable going into production is is
is what we.
Really want to drive towards. You know,
ideally we would want to reach a state
where we have enough confidence in our.
In our um.
In our in our test suite so that we would
feel that if we took a pull request and
it passed all of the the test automation
that we would feel comfortable merging it
to main and having that automatically
deployed into production.
So more of a a continuous.
In addition,
over on Bob what a continuous integration
we do,
this will be continuous deployment and
based and that basically allows us to
push small changes out into production
very rapidly.
And the final point is that it reduces
our maintenance burden because we have.
Much more consistent test suite that we
can rely on and then those automatic
quality gates that we're talking about in
your pipelines, you can then do,
you can do a minimum test coverage for
the creation of a PR but require more
more.
Extensive coverage for merging into into
into main.
You can include your linting and
architectural checks,
your Providence requirements so that you
make sure that a pull request has all of
that information that you want to be able
to to demonstrate for auditing purposes.
So you could do PR level test generation,
you can do risk scoring for changes.
All of these things are things that you
can consider leveraging AI to help you do.
So this will help you prevent regressions,
improve quality and and it supports this
Evergreen development mindset that we're.
That we're trying to adopt.
All right.
So we're getting close to the break. So.
So this is basically looking for
continuing this process of looking for
missing education, coverage gaps,
trying to continue to improve our.
Our our test suite.
So what we what we do is go ahead and
take our our our break and come back in
an hour and we can then finish up on this
this this testing exercise.
See you guys in a bit.
Thanks.